<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Laurent Smeets</title>
    <link>https://LaurentSmeets.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Laurent Smeets</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2018 18:56:13 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://LaurentSmeets.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian Regression in Blavaan (Using Stan)</title>
      <link>https://LaurentSmeets.github.io/tutorials/blavaan-regression-stan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2019 12:41:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://LaurentSmeets.github.io/tutorials/blavaan-regression-stan/</guid>
      <description>his tutorial provides the reader with a basic tutorial how to perform a Bayesian regression in Blavaan, using Stan instead of Jags as a MCMC sampler. You can find the Blavaan Jags tutorial here. We will not delve into the the differences between Stan and Jags here (a technical explanation can be found here and a more accessible blog post here). For now it suffices to say that Stan is more efficient, especially for complex models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WAMBS Blavaan Tutorial (Using Stan)</title>
      <link>https://LaurentSmeets.github.io/tutorials/blavaan-wambs-stan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2019 12:41:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://LaurentSmeets.github.io/tutorials/blavaan-wambs-stan/</guid>
      <description>In this tutorial you follow the steps of the When-to-Worry-and-How-to-Avoid-the-Misuse-of-Bayesian-Statistics – checklist the WAMBS-checklist. You can find a version of this tutorial using Jags instead of Stan here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian Regression in Blavaan (Using Jags)</title>
      <link>https://LaurentSmeets.github.io/tutorials/blavaan-regression-jags/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2018 12:41:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://LaurentSmeets.github.io/tutorials/blavaan-regression-jags/</guid>
      <description>This tutorial provides the reader with a basic tutorial how to perform a Bayesian regression in Blavaanm using Jags instead of Stan as a MCMC sampler. You can find the Blavaan Jags tutorial here. We will not delve into the the differences between Stan and Jags here (a technical explanation can be found here and a more accessible blog post here). For now it suffices to say that Stan is more efficient, especially for complex models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plausible Parameter Space, a R Shiny App</title>
      <link>https://LaurentSmeets.github.io/projects/pps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2018 12:41:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://LaurentSmeets.github.io/projects/pps/</guid>
      <description>This Shiny App is designed to help users define their priors in a linear regression with two regression coefficients. Users are asked to specify their plausible parameter space and their expected prior means and uncertainty around these means. The PhD-delay example, which is used as example in most other tutorials on this website, has been used an easy-to-go introduction to Bayesian inference. In this example the linear and quadratic effect of age on PhD-delay are estimated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regression in Lavaan</title>
      <link>https://LaurentSmeets.github.io/tutorials/lavaan-regression/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2018 12:41:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://LaurentSmeets.github.io/tutorials/lavaan-regression/</guid>
      <description>This tutorial provides the reader with a basic tutorial how to perform a regression analysis in lavaan. Throughout this tutorial, the reader will be guided through importing datafiles, exploring summary statistics and regression analyses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WAMBS Blavaan Tutorial (Using Jags)</title>
      <link>https://LaurentSmeets.github.io/tutorials/blavaan-wambs-jags/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2018 12:41:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://LaurentSmeets.github.io/tutorials/blavaan-wambs-jags/</guid>
      <description>In this tutorial you follow the steps of the When-to-Worry-and-How-to-Avoid-the-Misuse-of-Bayesian-Statistics –checklist (the WAMBS-checklist). You can find a version of this tutorial using Stan instead of Jags here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WAMBS Mplus Tutorial</title>
      <link>https://LaurentSmeets.github.io/tutorials/mplus-wambs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2018 12:41:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://LaurentSmeets.github.io/tutorials/mplus-wambs/</guid>
      <description>In this tutorial you follow the steps of the When-to-Worry-and-How-to-Avoid-the-Misuse-of-Bayesian-Statistics - checklist (the WAMBS-checklist) in Mplus</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BRMS Tutorial: Applying the WAMBS checklist</title>
      <link>https://LaurentSmeets.github.io/tutorials/brms-wambs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 12:41:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://LaurentSmeets.github.io/tutorials/brms-wambs/</guid>
      <description>In this tutorial you follow the steps of the When-to-Worry-and-How-to-Avoid-the-Misuse-of-Bayesian-Statistics – checklist (the WAMBS-checklist) for the multilevel model from the book Multilevel analysis: Techniques and applications, Chapter 2 In this manual the software package BRMS, version 2.3.1 for R (Windows) was use. This is part 3 of a 3 part series.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BRMS tutorial: the Influence of Priors</title>
      <link>https://LaurentSmeets.github.io/tutorials/brms-priors/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 12:41:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://LaurentSmeets.github.io/tutorials/brms-priors/</guid>
      <description>This tutorial shows how you can replicate the popularity data multilevel models from the book Multilevel analysis: Techniques and applications, Chapter 2, while using different priors. In this manual the software package BRMS, version 2.3.1 for R (Windows) was used. You will be playing around with the options in BRMS to adjust the priors as opposed to using the default prior settings as we used in the BRMS Tutorial. This is part 2 of a 3 part series.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Bayesian Multilevel Model in BRMS Tutorial: Popularity Data</title>
      <link>https://LaurentSmeets.github.io/tutorials/brms-how-to-get-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 12:41:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://LaurentSmeets.github.io/tutorials/brms-how-to-get-started/</guid>
      <description>This tutorial shows how you can replicate the popularity data multilevel models from the book Multilevel analysis: Techniques and applications, Chapter 2. In this manual the software package BRMS, version 2.3.1 for R (Windows) was used. Results should be very similar to results obtained with other software packages, however due to convergence and rounding issues, you might notice minor differences. This is part 1 of a 3 part series</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LME4 Tutorial: Popularity Data</title>
      <link>https://LaurentSmeets.github.io/tutorials/lme4-how-to-get-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 12:41:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://LaurentSmeets.github.io/tutorials/lme4-how-to-get-started/</guid>
      <description>This document shows how you can replicate the popularity data multilevel models from the book Multilevel analysis: Techniques and applications, Chapter 2. In this tutorial, the software packages LME4 and lmerTest for R (Windows) were used. Results should be very similar to results obtained with other software packages, however due to convergence and rounding issues, you might notice minor differences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HLM Tutorial: Popularity Data</title>
      <link>https://LaurentSmeets.github.io/tutorials/hlm7-how-to-get-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2018 12:41:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://LaurentSmeets.github.io/tutorials/hlm7-how-to-get-started/</guid>
      <description>This document shows how you can replicate the popularity data multilevel models from Multilevel analysis: Techniques and applications (Hox, J. J., Moerbeek, M., &amp;amp; van de Schoot, R, 2018), Chapter 2. In this manual the software package HLM7 for Windows was used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mplus Tutorial: Popularity Data</title>
      <link>https://LaurentSmeets.github.io/tutorials/mplus-multilevel-how-to-get-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2018 12:41:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://LaurentSmeets.github.io/tutorials/mplus-multilevel-how-to-get-started/</guid>
      <description>This document shows how you can replicate the popularity data multilevel models from Multilevel analysis: Techniques and applications (Hox, J. J., Moerbeek, M., &amp;amp; van de Schoot, R, 2018), Chapter 2. In this manual the software package Mplus version 8 for Windows was used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian Regression in Mplus</title>
      <link>https://LaurentSmeets.github.io/tutorials/mplus-regression-bayesian/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2018 12:41:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://LaurentSmeets.github.io/tutorials/mplus-regression-bayesian/</guid>
      <description>This tutorial provides the reader with a basic tutorial how to perform a Bayesian regression in Mplus. Throughout this tutorial, the reader will be guided through importing data files, exploring summary statistics and regression analyses. Here, we will exclusively focus on Bayesian statistics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://LaurentSmeets.github.io/hello/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://LaurentSmeets.github.io/hello/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search Results</title>
      <link>https://LaurentSmeets.github.io/search/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://LaurentSmeets.github.io/search/</guid>
      <description>This file exists solely to respond to /search URL with the related search layout template.
No content shown here is rendered, all content is based in the template layouts/page/search.html
Setting a very low sitemap priority will tell search engines this is not important content.
This implementation uses Fusejs, jquery and mark.js
Initial setup Search depends on additional output content type of JSON in config.toml
[outputs] home = [&amp;quot;HTML&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;JSON&amp;quot;]  Searching additional fileds To search additional fields defined in front matter, you must add it in 2 places.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>